# **Matthew Reinke**

■ reinkedev@gmail.com □ 4012086669

### **SUMMARY**

Lifelong artist with over 16 years experience as a Designer, Art Director, and Producer in the video game space. I streamline processes and herd cats of creative geniuses with workflow, design expertise, and contagious enthusiasm; bringing complex ideas to reality through rapid prototyping and hard work.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Lead Level Designer**

#### Meeti2i

May 2020 - August 2024, San Francisco, CA

- · Created 2D levels in 'Tiled' for proprietary video conferencing product.
- · Created custom levels for clients.
- · Worked with art to make custom assets function properly.
- · Defined Best Practices for content creation.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Created content pipeline for level creation.

## Senior Level Designer

Glu Mobile

January 2018 - April 2020, San Mateo, CA

- Established and maintained production pipeline and file structure best practices.
- $\cdot \ \text{Designed layouts in photoshop and prototyped in Unity using height maps; bringing them to finished quality.}$
- $\cdot$  Designed and populated animal gameplay in 'Deer Hunter' mobile game.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Created, iterated on, and maintained all animal behavior flow graphs.
- · Managed live ops, updating game designs as needed on the fly to match user demands and redesigns using analytics and AB testing.

### **Lead Level Designer**

### Flatter than Earth

February 2016 - January 2018, San Francisco, CA

- Established and maintained production pipeline and file structure best practices.
- · Prototyped camera operation and behavior.
- Prototyped levels and puzzles in Unity.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Prototyped game mechanics.
- · Critiqued and supported 3D art construction in Maya.
- Provided concept art critique and general art direction.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Operated in Scrum methodology using Jira.
- · Using Unity analytics, gathered and deciphered test play data to determine average lengths of play, puzzle difficulty, player fatigue, heatmaps, and anomalous events.

#### Art Director and Lead Designer

#### **Powerhouse Games**

May 2013 - November 2015, Folsom, CA

- Operated as Lead Designer creating flowcharts and wireframes; bringing them to final design using MindMapper and Invision for cloud design collaboration.
- · Led a team of 2 artists, 2 engineers, and 1 QA.Ran live ops on new releases, observing AB data and adjusting elements based on game performance.
- Designed game themes, mini-games, UI/UX, as well as the related separate terminal systems so that users can purchase credits, link to a terminal, and have gaming funds available.
- Functioned as Art Director defining company style and quality bars, including critiquing and updating existing products and branding. Created design and art pipelines, best practices, and internal management/invoice proprietary tools.
- · Led art department as final authority on game design/art providing daily guidance to reach and maintain established product goals.
- $\cdot \ \text{Created 2D art for marketing and terminal UI use.} Designed \ \text{and tasked all audio for various games}.$
- · Operated as scrum master for the design/art team, running daily scrum meetings and overseeing sprints using Sprintly.
- · Created webpage updates and marketing release packages for public release.
- · Created arcade cabinet art using Photoshop.

### **World Builder**

#### **Tencent Boston**

April 2010 - March 2013, Concord, MA

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Led a team of 4 interns in level construction.
- · Set best practices and workflow pipeline.
- · Created prefab packages for quick level iteration.
- · Created hundreds of game levels in Unity for the game 'Robot Rising' using a proprietary grid system.

- · Set up lighting in both 'Robot Rising' and our unreleased MMO.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Story boarded, recorded, and edited game trailers.
- · Constructed and recorded all gameplay and milestone cinematics using Unity and Premiere.
- · Created 7 massive player zones in an unreleased MMO.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Provided feedback for the art team on asset look and usage.

### **Level Designer**

**Blue Fang Games** 

May 2008 - March 2010, Waltham, MA

- · Prototyped and designed gameplay in 3DS Max for Nintendo Wii game 'World of Zoo'.
- Populated levels with 'navspheres,' defining where animals move and walk on exhibit geometry.
- · Populated levels with interaction points so animals would perform specific animations and behaviors appropriately.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Created a content pipeline in 3DS Max and Wii Devkit.

### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor's degree in 2D Painting

University of Massachusetts Dartmouth · Dartmouth, MA · 2007

· President of the Paint club.

C	77	TT.	т	C
	ĸ		ı.	

UI

English

Confluence

Jira

Unity

MindMapper

Maya

Invision

YEd

Sprintly

UDK

Adobe Creative Suite

Perforce

Sourcetree

FRAPS

Camtasia

VLC

**OCam** 

Painting

Waterfall

Proprietary tool development

**SCRUM** 

UX

System Design

Wireframing

Agile